The City Council for today's date and time called to order item two is
public input and unscheduled personal journalism appearances and we need the
audience wish to address the city council on any of the agenda items.
There are being none item three as a consent agenda staff is recommending items four and
five which are claims in minutes for the February 20 meeting.
If there are no questions or corrections to the minutes would entertain a motion to
approve the consent agenda and the second roll call please.
Jonathan Westin forster Lewis Schultz.
Item six is capital ventures government relations LLC March claim of 3,000.
I think we had one of these at our last meeting was that the February claim maybe
I'm remembering.
I think we were back on schedule of having it on our first meeting every month.
It was a set of meeting last time because we were.
Okay.
Any questions or comments on this item?
If not, do we have a motion?
I'll make a motion.
Okay.
Do we have a second?
Second.
Roll call please.
Forster.
Western.
Lewis.
Johnson.
Shultz.
Item seven is new business and new business anyone.
Item eight is staff reports.
Again, written reports on your package available and staff is present for questions if
they're aren't.
I just got a question for them.
Relations.
And I.
I have to be a little research because we still have.
I speak at our.
I have a show.
No.
That's a good thing.
We've got.
Have taken about forty some.
To rest.
Here in the past two months.
I asked them today and we have about 18 or 19 in the new shelter.
And that can change in a day.
I mean, you know, but we have.
Three open pans in the old shelter.
So that means that we will be bringing some number to the new shelter once they've met their quarantine.
But.
No, we are not at the pass to be right now.
So that's awesome.
Okay.
I'm not familiar with the new shelter all shelter.
The shelter that we have.
Right.
Before we built a new and we've committed to the quarantine shelter.
Okay.
And that's where we keep them for the three business days.
Or if we have one, we had one recently that had an open source.
So we moved it over into what we call the quarantine shelter.
And once they've done the time there, then we move over into the adoption shelter.
And that's the one that we left the public come in.
We also keep any vicious animals or anyone that we're holding for a court case or anything.
Like that the old shelter.
So that that when we just kind of have a.
a separation in it. It helps determine diseases or anything possibly happen. So when we
turn with quarantine shelter, we adopt shelter. Well, I know we refer a long time
that's been a capacity as, and our number, the animal thing, we've now is going up, cause of that.
No, it has not. Can you, can you give me something comparison? Probably was a year ago, until
a year ago, whatever, I mean, we've never seen that in a shelter. Or just in the last year,
or what, the animals that we need to know is, it has been up since this time last year. It's what I'm saying.
No, it isn't. We still follow the quality of life protocol that we have. We will keep them,
and when we start seeing their quality of life deteriorate, we'll start assessing them,
and when we do determine that their quality of life, and when we use it to start really
looking part out of it about six months, because an animal being in there for six months,
you can start seeing their attitude, go down, you can see them start getting distant, or some of them
will get aggressive, and we've just, we've pretty much been able to keep it, to where we go,
use an eyes, probably, through a small month, maybe, is what we're looking at. I mean, that's,
that's kind of an average of what we are, and those are all because they've been there too long.
We also, if they're really, really sick, if they come in, or if they're aggressive,
and they are non-adoptable, that they don't never make it into the shelter, so.
So, most kinds of things, because of the health of the animals.
Most cases, it's because of the animal. We do not use an eyes, because we're out of where we always find some places
for them to go, or sometimes we'll find two dogs that really get along well. We might double up with them
before that full, but we've been extremely fortunate, and that's probably only happened to
hand full of times after they do that. So, the shampoo, the shards, works, and the welfare of the
option agency, really well with us, really close with us, and she has a great network that we send
into Colorado, Minnesota, Iowa, several. In our place, and here are the public tech pit pools, or
we have a government tax pit pool, Shannon's own, and the casher, and we have a lot of big stuff
still in the water to prevent it, and we have five of those that might have happened to it.
Okay, and then some of the important dollars that I'm just thinking of, didn't work out, so.
So, at least your my understanding of the process might not be the right word, but
the animal control officer, or perhaps you, someone in the chain and the line of authority there,
ultimately has a discretion to make a decision on whether to use the knives and animal right on.
And the way you just described it, that process, and what if they're...
If they want to do it, okay, let's set those aside, if they're healthy animal, it could be
four or five, six months before an animal that's utilized.
It could be longer than six months because we don't even really have to six months but
dogs do really really well and we, when they're in the quarantine, they get a daily assessment.
When they move into the adoption shelter, they get a weekly assessment and when we start
notice a net about six months, so we start really really paying close attention and really
watching them. But up until six months, we try to do everything again to get them adopted
and keep them up to everything again.
How do you communicate with you said Shanda and I'm sure there's other people besides you?
How do they become aware that those are animal there for adoption? I mean, do they
come by once a week or do you send them a list or how does that work?
In the pictures that we put them on, we put all out of Facebook but because we do work so closely
with Shanda, we will send her pictures at, when they're at there at a month, when they're there at two
months, three months, four months, five months and at five months, she really starts pushing to try to
get them into a rescue and start really networking and have people on. She works all the way through it
but we also want to be able to adopt them out to recoup self-sufficiency. So we, at five months,
she really starts working with this, but we put pictures out and we have a board that we put them up there.
We have a lot of people that will call and just ask if you're going to need a dog for adoption and we'll
kind of run through it for them and invite them up to look at them. Is there any plan for this spring and
something like that one weekend started that people who come out just have a day where they walk the
dog and just go on the big ground out there for adoption. Especially, we haven't done that yet. I mean,
we're open to every Saturday and we have volunteers that are out there doing to bring them to the
farmers' market one day. We do bring them to farmers' market at least one time, but that's
the week and on the Thursday. Our staffing is somewhat short on trying to take care of the dogs.
So if we have volunteers out there walking in every Saturday anyway, anyone that wants to come and walk
dogs is welcome to come any time Saturday or Sunday. So we're there Saturdays and we love for people to come
and it is amazing to me how many volunteers that do come and help us out. So
I'm just making a big deal to have this. I can especially adopt them better or something.
What's up? What's up? What's up? What's up? What's up? What's up?
And they always take blankets and towels. We can always take blankets and towels. Yes, we just had someone
don't let go of food today. So. Okay.
Thanks, Lation.
Hey, Lation, let's stay close.
We're going to get to the top of this question.
OK.
So, do you want to do that under item eight?
Do you want to wait and do that under?
No, I don't want to do that.
All right.
So item nine, mayor and council committee announcements.
Any, OK?
Item 10, man, is city manager communication?
slide to slide.
I think that's the issue.
I've been out of this all afternoon,
but it's looking to be like we've
probably going to be bringing the splash fat out of the point here.
We are hopefully hopefully to bring the architect and the CMAR
actual contract to then Georgia has it right now.
She's one of those where the scope is to make sure that we're not paying people to do the same job.
And hopefully we're going to have it to you for then start making a design on this one.
So I just wanted to give you that up there on where that stands and we hope that's going to be on the next
agenda.
And one quick question, the test wells, are they going to be in the building of the splash
panel?
Are they going to propose a problem?
Well, we set down on the architect to do the designing that will all be factored in and looked
at it.
And I know that they said that happen, they're still sticking out because they are going to adjust
that to where the ground level is and everything once we get the design.
So they will exist there until they're clear enough.
They will exist there.
Yeah.
They're going to get all of them be there.
Yes.
But they're not going to be at the end of a part of the panel.
No, no, no, no.
You said it's not a foundation.
Yeah.
No, they won't be.
It will be in the four acres side to be at the flow test wells will be there, probably for a long
long time.
But the corporation of the design and splash panel, not have the test wells to be removed.
We've all said we're going to have a splash panel.
This is the path the wells are over here, so we'll be very mindful that they're there.
I mean, they won't be forgotten.
Okay.
So.
And we already have kind of a store of, I think we're going to be using the top sort of, I don't
know, by the second one.
Yes.
And I've been in touch with OVE and we're working with them to maybe get some fill and things
and what we're doing.
We have a store of top sort of everybody all by the new one, especially in the industrial part.
And that's what we're going to use for the soil.
Okay.
So you don't know where you're going to have to look at it.
I was going to say it's those wells are sticking up pretty far.
Exactly.
Yeah.
And you realize we're going to be a lot of things under the splash pad, so that's splash
panel we built up and we'll have to bring it further.
So you will have to put the plumbing underground, you discover it.
Yes.
Yeah.
And then also, I was in a meeting that that would be talking about this meeting at our next
study section.
But I was at a meeting with E.K.
At the end.
They just picked one.
Because we talked about another thing related to CHAP, but they were a book who said,
as soon as we get this done.
They're ready to kind of have for the final radiation testing to make sure that there's no traffic
she's on that problem. That's what's going to happen. Because Oethy is ready to go on actually.
And I talked to our purpose in a Brian and depending on me, because we might come up quite a bit,
you know, by the time you build everything up, it might be that they didn't bring in dirt,
because depending upon how hot and how deep. They call them encapsulate. Right, they encapsulate it.
So we'll, like, say, we're working on that. Okay. So on this design phase, I know you're going to have a group of people
that's, when do you predict that they're going to be getting together? I would say, as soon as we get that contract done,
we'll get with the architect and see how soon they want us to meet with there if they want to come
to the group with plans, or if they want to have the group meet before they ever have plans,
and we'll go from there. So I don't want to tell you two weeks. I don't want to tell you
it's pretty weeks and then be long. I know, we are. I'm pushing every day to get it done. So,
thank you. Thank you. I have a few other things that I want to say. First off,
I think it's an update on our activities to grant, and we have that in your service.
I'm going to talk about the seat on the hard plastic.
I don't want to talk about that. You're ready to do this, thank you.
At the bike work, everyone must talk about it.
I know Steve, in the end of his speaking, gave $10,000 to my type of skills for the wrestling
right around the weight room, weight room, and so on.
The one I've said about the thing about the water bottle.
We're around the water bottle, so I think we'll have it in the seat of the meeting next week,
and I'm at the National Substance Commission there to go to the MCFA to come here on that sign.
And I talked to the boundary, the boundary, and it's interesting if you've ever heard 3D print.
That is how to reproduce the extension. It's like the scan of the extension of the water.
And then he's the 3D printer. Now they have basically a foam form for the extension of the values
in the clay from the bottle, and that's what the raws would be like. So they're building right along the extensions,
so it's the whole project. It's really good to see Steve, I saw this.
And if you didn't know that the planning is, if any other kind of skills will,
is to have that battling first war dog game, which is always starting first.
That's the hope in the planning.
And fundraising is under what you have.
And speaking of Steve, I'll let's see the traffic signal as Steve opens the main stream.
last about it today, you know, the last rain, it just is still, you get it led, it just goes into
flash, it's the list of all, but this is there, and I will take care of that problem, so it's
just a state pain for that, so it's a state pain for most of the workers, yeah, we have
a set of big ones, so we're happy about that. Two final things we want to talk about is we
started moving into the new offices today, so it started with the furniture, it's probably
going to be about a four-week process, a lot of it's going to be computers, a computer set,
other than the furniture set, I don't know that, I don't know when we're going to have a first
meeting in the new council check, so we'll try to get you, heads up on what we do that, and how
you work great in the new council check, we're actually able to occupy this area and start
with the offices, very happy about that. And finally, last and certainly not least, Citywide
Cleanup, I think this is a fourth year now, a week since we've researched Citywide Cleanup, and
on the week of March 12, we'll be doing the Northwest of South West sections of the city, and we'll be
doing March 19, we'll be doing the Northeast and the Southeast sections of the city, of course,
we'll let this on our face to change, we'll work with the Newspaper to get word out, community
development already, and thereafter we'll work with the people that need to clean it up to let
them know that this is coming, so it's probably the best time in the year for them to clean up
their properties, so it's getting started, when we do everything we can, it's got a lot of
group running off hands on deck, so people need to be, we might not get to a part of those good
things, some people would like us to get the community to clean up this, it's that, and we
started in our courts and we started in our, we started in our, we started in our, this is
time, this is started, it's the city, you have a contact, you have a contact, you have a contact
issue, you've got to be on the side of the deck, yeah, yeah that's always fine, fine, I'll let you say
walk around, I'm curious about that, that one's pretty familiar with that, so, people are already
putting stuff out, I suppose there are things today, but at least people are catching
on a person, I, I think we've seen increases in time, very good, yeah, yeah, so those are
more important, yeah, so those are my reports, okay, the questions for Dean or anything, okay,
item 11 is it's the executive session pursuant to 25, 0, s, 3, 0, 7, b, 1 for purposes of discussing the
employment hiring, the portion of this funding, or the resignation of any individual salary, public
officer employee to what Dean Krutov, do we have a motion to go on the executive session
and a second, okay.